portfolio: chrisstack.co

chris@chrisstack.co

(715) 557-1886

SUMMARY

Web developer with six years experience building web applications. Mostly focused on the front-end with a strong background in JavaScript using ES6 and libraries like Vue and React. Also proficient with back-end and database technologies such as Node, PHP/ Laravel and SQL. Strong problem solver with excellent communication and collaboration skills. Focused on writing clean, testable code in a highly productive manner.

EXPERIENCE

The Lacek Group (July 2018 – April 2020)

- Owned the architecture and implementation of the front-end for multiple sites and web apps.
- Utilized Vue.js and Laravel Blade for creating repeatable templates and components to avoid duplication which increased production.

Developed:

- Components and added CSS for an event bidding web app that reached over 1 million visitors.
- Components for forms, tabs, carousels and other common UI features that more fully met semantic and accessibilty requirements than frameworks like Bootstrap.
- Interactive world map that displayed hotel locations based on category. Included filter by category and clustering nearby locations to avoid display clutter.
- Site where dev team could easily upload individual email campaign data to display for client. Made optimizations over the life of the project including adding image lazy loading once multiple hundreds of email campaigns were live.
- Video player with autoplay toggle.
- Interactive calendar to select a range of dates to book a hotel stay.

Personal (September 2014 – Current)

- Designed, developed, and currently hosting several web applications for businesses and personal side projects.
- Build sites with a focus on responsive design and semantic markup for SEO and web accessibility. For one client, this helped lead to a traffic increase from 20 to 150 users per month over an eight month period, which led to increased business.
- Developed an application that displays the time, current weather, and upcoming weather. Used React for the view layer. Used the Geolocation API to get user's location coordinates based off IP address. Used Fetch API to retrieve weather data from the RESTful OpenWeatherMap API.
- Developed two web games based on board games. Currently adding two player functionality for one of them using web sockets.

Cazarin Interactive (September 2016 – November 2017)

- Created 12 complete, responsive websites including eCommerce, Booking, and static sites. Collaborated on over 10 other sites adding features or pages.
- Used PHP and JavaScript for editing plugin and template files and interacting with the DOM. Used MySQL for importing, exporting, and querying databases.
- Used Bootstrap for quickly creating features and streamlining responsive design.

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML Node PHP / Laravel CSS / Sass Bootstrap SQL / NoSQL

JavaScript / ES6 Webpack / Gulp Git

Vue / React GraphQL / REST Headless CMS

QUALIFICATIONS

- Productivity focused This is my main concern. The more tasks I accomplish, the more I feel like a successful developer. My subsequent qualifications feed into this one.
- Logical and systematic problem solver I solve problems effectively by making sure I understand the problem fully before attacking it, breaking it up into smaller, more manageable pieces, and using a variety of pertinent resources.
- Detail Oriented I place a lot of importance on the finer details of a project. I never want a user to find something out of place on a project I made. I believe what sets a high quality project apart from an average one is the details. With this in mind, I'm constantly scanning for issues and brainstorming unique edge cases when developing.
- Work effectively in collaborative environments I enjoy offering my input when collaborating on a project. I find it exciting bouncing ideas off of others when working through problems. I'm often pretty self-reliant but can also identify when I should ask for help or clarification.
- Strong organizational and time management skills I like to make lists or work logs when planning and tracking projects. Besides creating a sense of accomplishment when a task is complete, it also helps prioritize tasks, prevents features being left out, and provides an estimate of how long tasks, and therefore the overall project, should take.

EDUCATION

University of Saint Thomas, Saint Paul, Minnesota Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering — December 2014

- Semester long computer science class on programming fundamentals and the C language.
- Completed electrical engineering projects involving programming LEDs to sync with melodies and a digital stopwatch.